<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-21T11:06:24+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Laboratory of Multi-omic Integrative Bioinformatics</title><subtitle>WELCOME TO THE LABORATORY OF MULTI-OMIC INTEGRATIVE BIOINFORMATICS (LMIB)</subtitle><entry><title type="html">LMIBeaches Win Third Place in VIB Beach Volley Tournament!</title><link href="/2025/07/01/beachvolleyball.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LMIBeaches Win Third Place in VIB Beach Volley Tournament!" /><published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-21T11:02:05+00:00</updated><id>/2025/07/01/beachvolleyball</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/07/01/beachvolleyball.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<!-- excerpt end -->
<p>From code to court, the LMIBeaches proved that the LMIB can bring the heat. With sharp plays and even sharper focus, our team secured a solid third place in the VIB Beach Volley Tournament. Congratulations to the squad for showing that LMIBeaches can dominate the sand, too!</p>

<div style="display: flex; flex-wrap: wrap; justify-content: center; gap: 10px;">

  <div style="flex: 1 1 45%; max-width: 45%;">
    <figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="figure link">
    <img src="/images/news/LMIBeaches-2025.jpg" style="
        width: 100%;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="figure image" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
</figure>

  </div>

  <div style="flex: 1 1 45%; max-width: 45%;">
    <figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="figure link">
    <img src="/images/news/LMIBeaches-2025-2.JPG" style="
        width: 100%;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="figure image" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
</figure>

  </div>

  <div style="flex: 1 1 90%; max-width: 90%; margin-top: 5px;">
    <figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="figure link">
    <img src="/images/news/LMIBeaches-2025-3.jpg" style="
        width: 100%;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="figure image" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
</figure>

  </div>

</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="awards" /><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From code to court, the LMIBeaches proved that the LMIB can bring the heat. With sharp plays and even sharper focus, our team secured a solid third place in the VIB Beach Volley Tournament. Congratulations to the squad for showing that LMIBeaches can dominate the sand, too!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the team Vasiliki!</title><link href="/2025/05/01/welcome-spring2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the team Vasiliki!" /><published>2025-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-21T11:02:05+00:00</updated><id>/2025/05/01/welcome-spring2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/05/01/welcome-spring2025.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>Welcoming our Newest PhD Student Vasiliki!
<!-- excerpt end --></p>

<p>We are excited to welcome our newest PhD student, Vasiliki, to the LMIB team!
Vasiliki will collaborate with fellow PhD student Fatemeh to advance our understanding of congenital heart disease (CHD), a leading cause of non-infectious child mortality. Under the joint supervision of Alejandro and <a href="https://www.uzleuven.be/en/physicians-and-specialists/jeroen-breckpot">Jeroen Breckpot</a> from UZ Leuven, she will use long-read whole genome sequencing to identify gene-phenotype associations and to better characterize complex genetic variation in CHD.
Her work will be part of the DeepHeart Project, a multi-laboratory initiative dedicated to identifying specific genes involved in non-syndromic congenital heart disease (NS-CHD).</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcoming our Newest PhD Student Vasiliki!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the team Fatemeh and Saptarshi!</title><link href="/2024/11/01/welcome-fall2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the team Fatemeh and Saptarshi!" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-21T11:02:05+00:00</updated><id>/2024/11/01/welcome-fall2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/11/01/welcome-fall2024.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>Welcoming our Newest PhD Student Fatemeh, and Data Engineer Saptarshi!
<!-- excerpt end --></p>

<p>We are thrilled to welcome our newest PhD student Fatemeh and our new data engineer Saptarshi to the LMIB team! 
Fatemeh will work on advancing our understanding of congenital heart disease (CHD), a leading cause of non-infectious child mortality by developing novel deep learning-based computational methods to prioritize candidate genes. With the DeepHeart Project, she aims to identify specific genes that are likely involved in non-syndromic congenital heart disease (NS-CHD).</p>

<p>Saptarshi will design and implement scalable data architecture to efficiently manage LISCO’s high-throughput single-cell and spatial omics data. He will oversee workflows from raw data generation in wet labs to AI model training and deployment by computational teams, ensuring models are continually updated to maintain accuracy and keep LISCO at the forefront of the field.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcoming our Newest PhD Student Fatemeh, and Data Engineer Saptarshi!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Congrats Nacho for Winning Best Presentation at LISCO Single Cell Day 2024!</title><link href="/2024/10/22/nacho-lisco2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Congrats Nacho for Winning Best Presentation at LISCO Single Cell Day 2024!" /><published>2024-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-21T11:02:05+00:00</updated><id>/2024/10/22/nacho-lisco2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/10/22/nacho-lisco2024.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<!-- excerpt end -->
<p>Congratulations to our colleague Nacho for winning the Best Presentation Award at this year’s <a href="https://lisco.kuleuven.be/single-cell-day-2024">LISCO Single Cell Day 2024</a>. His presentation on <strong>AI-based spatial multi-omic data fusion</strong> was recognized for its innovation and engaging delivery.</p>

<p>In his presentation, Nacho introduced an AI-driven approach to learning data representations that capture both shared and modality-specific variability across different omics layers. This method enhances our understanding of the complex interactions between these layers by disentangling shared variations from sample-specific biases and enabling cross-modal translation when one data modality is absent. He demonstrated the power of this neural network architecture using a prostate cancer dataset, showcasing how spatial multi-omics data, combined with cutting-edge AI techniques, can accurately predict detailed pathologist annotations.</p>

<p>We are proud to have an inspiring researcher pushing the boundaries of multi-omic integration in our lab, and this achievement is well deserved.</p>

<p>Here’s to many more successes ahead!</p>

<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="figure link">
    <img src="/images/news/nacho-lisco2024.jpg" style="
        width: 75%;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="figure image" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="awards" /><category term="LISCO" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations to our colleague Nacho for winning the Best Presentation Award at this year’s LISCO Single Cell Day 2024. His presentation on AI-based spatial multi-omic data fusion was recognized for its innovation and engaging delivery.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the team Anis, Jelle and Lorenzo!</title><link href="/2024/10/01/welcome-fall2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the team Anis, Jelle and Lorenzo!" /><published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-21T11:02:05+00:00</updated><id>/2024/10/01/welcome-fall2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/10/01/welcome-fall2024.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>Welcoming our Newest PhD Students Anis and Lorenzo, and Research Associate Jelle!
<!-- excerpt end --></p>

<p>We are thrilled to welcome Anis and Lorenzo, our incoming PhD students, and Jelle, our new research associate, to the LMIB team! Anis will extend his previous thesis work in Explainable AI and apply it to multi-omic integration models along other models developed at the lab, and Lorenzo will propose new techniques to improve our current implementation of multi-omics integration models. 
Jelle’s extensive experience as a researcher will help bring new perspectives and push the boundaries of our research even further. We are looking forward to the exciting research and collaboration ahead with such a talented and diverse group!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcoming our Newest PhD Students Anis and Lorenzo, and Research Associate Jelle!]]></summary></entry></feed>